Joseph C McDade

4609 Brookview Rd Rockford, IL 61107 (815) 298-6912 Joseph@McDade.info https://github.com/FlexibleToast

Summary of Qualifications

- Cleared for TS/SCI work
- Experience administrating Windows, UNIX, and Linux
- Proficient with C/C++, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS,
 PHP, and bash languages

Personal Goals

To give back to humanity using knowledge learned while serving and studying. To continue my growth as a programmer and develop innovative technology for future generations.

Education

Rock Valley College

Jan 2005 - Dec 2008

Associate in Applied Science - AAS, Criminal Justice with Honors

Community College of the Air Force

Sep 2010 - Apr 2013

- Associate in Applied Science AAS, Information Systems Technology
- Focused on System Administration

Northern Illinois University

Jan 2015 - Dec 2018

- Bachelor of Science BS, Computer Science with a minor in General Mathematics
- Graduated Summa Cum Laude with Upper Division University Honors
- Learned proficiency in C/C++, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, PHP, and bash scripting
- Focused degree in data analytics with:
 - Co-authored paper published in *Journal of Computing in Higher Education* using network modeling to look at the interaction of participants in a MOOC titled, *The nature and level of learner-learner interaction in a chemistry Massive Open Online Course (MOOC)*. Paper can be found at DOI: 10.1007/s12528-017-9144-2
 - Author of unpublished honors capstone research paper about using machine learning techniques to predict reproducibility of research titled, Can We Predict Reproducible Scholarly Research? Paper can be found at http://commons.lib.niu.edu/handle/10843/17880

Professional Certifications

CompTIA Security+

Security Clearance

Clearance for Top Secret Information and granted access to Sensitive Compartmented Information (TS/SCI) based on single scope background investigation completed on 12 January 2018.

Professional Experience

US Air Force - 3D0X2 Cyber Systems Operations

Sep 2010 - Sep 2014

- Worked at an Air and Space Operations Center supporting the Falconer weapon system
- Installed/Configured/Maintained Windows, Windows Server, and Solaris UNIX clients and servers
- Used network based imaging software to deploy Windows clients
- Performed user account management with Windows Active Directory including: creation, deletion, assigning of rights and permissions, creating storage quotas for home drive and user profiles
- Created, implemented, and tested backup and recovery strategies

Illinois Air National Guard - 3D0X2 Cyber Systems Operations

Sep 2014 - Present

In addition to duties performed at previous position in USAF active duty:

- Used new knowledge to automate many routine administrative tasks through scripting
- Use Windows System Center Configuration Manager (SCCM) to create and deploy packages. Keeping software patched and deploying new software.